Shubhangi Mundhada

Frisco, Texas || (832)-715-8716 || shubhimundhada@gmail.com

Summary:

A full stack software engineer with more than 3 years of experiences in web and application developments. I merge a passion for usability and user experience with technical knowledge to create intriguing digital experience. My repertoire includes **React**, **HTML/CSS**, .NetCore, **JavaScript**, MSSQL & Java.

Degrees:

❖ Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering with Honors
 University of Houston, Cullen College of Engineering (Honors)
 Aug. 2014 – Dec. 2017

❖ Master of Science in Management and Information Systems
 University of Texas, Naveen School of Business (Pursuing)
 Aug. 2020 − Present

Certifications:

- ❖ Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp University of Texas at Austin
- * Certified ISO 9001 Internal Auditor

Skills:

- ❖ Languages: JAVA, C/C++, Verilog, MATLAB
- Frontend: React, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap
- ❖ Backend: MSSQL, MangoDB, Mongoose, NodeJS, ExpressJS
- ❖ Frameworks: .NetCore, XCode, Android Studio, Eclipse, MS Visual Studio
- Application: PowerBuilder, Adobe Photoshop, MS Office, MS Project, MS Visio.
- * Tools: GitHub, GitLab, Confluence, Jira, Business Intelligence Tools (SSRS & SSAS)

Professional Experience:

JSW Steel USA Inc – Baytown, TX

May 2016 – Present

* Application Developer

Mar 2018 – Present

- Designed and implemented UI via a web application that calculates production and inventory values and provides valuable analytics regarding daily production activities.
- Proposed and developed a scalable solution to auto-generate reports in real-time, which took away user interference from PPC controls, and improved client efficiency by 95%.
- Conduct internal audits periodically in the company to monitor mechanism so that they are in accordance with the ISO 9001 requirements.
- Developed UI application for the shipping area to eliminate periodic and redundant tasks, which improved accuracy by a significant amount.
- Created application for the Metallurgy department to retrieve production data and gather risk analysis on reject and rework material.

- Contribute ideas to provide a better understanding to clients, not just limited to the application development realm.
- Used Jira and Confluence to create a data flow structure to better manage the scope of the project, leading to completion in a given time.

* IT Intern

May 2017- Aug. 2017

- Network:
 - Assisted with maintenance and monitoring various network services and related devices.
 - Remapped company's network system using MS Visio, documented network related problems and recommended potential solutions.
- Android Development:
 - Developed android app to enable access to production and shipment reports on cellular devices.

Software Intern

May 2016-Aug. 2016

- Created various reports according to company's requirement. Deployed and managed reports using SQL Server Reporting Services.
- Created cubes and dimensions using SQL Server Analysis Services so company can utilize it to analyze performance.

Relevant Engineering Coursework: ~Data Structures ~Automatic Control Systems ~Adv. Digital Design ~Embedded Microprocessor ~Computer Architecture ~Fund. Software Engr. ~Digital Electronics ~Fund. Medical Imaging

Membership:

•	Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)	Aug. 2014 –Present
•	Eta Epsilon Rho (Honors Engineering Program)	Aug. 2014 - Dec.2017
•	Students Association (ISA)	Aug. 2014 - Dec.2017
•	Pratham (Graphic Designer Officer)	May. 2016 - Present